<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>notes on Ayrat's Braindump</title><link>https://braindump.badykov.com/tags/notes/</link><description>Recent content in notes on Ayrat's Braindump</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://braindump.badykov.com/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My braindump</title><link>https://braindump.badykov.com/notes/20210831225847-my_braindump/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://braindump.badykov.com/notes/20210831225847-my_braindump/</guid><description>My Braindump is generated with ox-hugo from my Org-Roam notes. The current idea for it is to be my personal knowledge system.
Related links: github repo - my braindump is hosted on github with github pages cortex-dark - hugo theme for the braindump Backlog: Simplify the process of exporting notes
Maintain two sets of notes.</description></item><item><title>Networking notes</title><link>https://braindump.badykov.com/notes/20220625105915-networking_notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://braindump.badykov.com/notes/20220625105915-networking_notes/</guid><description>OSI Model 7 layers that standartize networks Not used anymore - tcp / ip is sued Layers Physical - cable Data link - mac address Network - ip address, routing Transport - TCP / UDP Session - start / stop sessions Presentation - format data, encryption Application - SMTP (email) TCP/IP model Created to standartize computer networking
Application - application protocols (http, smtp, ftp) - DATA Transport - TCP/UDP protocols - SEGMENT Network - IP - PACKET Data link - ETHERNET - FRAME Physical - Cable TCP vs UDP TCP Used when good and reliable connection is needed (for example to download files) Two computers ack the connection before it takes place.</description></item><item><title>Org-Roam</title><link>https://braindump.badykov.com/notes/20210831213556-org_roam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://braindump.badykov.com/notes/20210831213556-org_roam/</guid><description>org-roam is a plain-text knowledge management system. It uses org-mode files. Initiallly, org-roam was developed as a Roam research clone.
I use org-roam almost for all my notes and my braindump is generated from my org-roam notes
Some thoughts about note-taking :
It seems you have to make the effort to take notes. Otherwise your notes are useless</description></item><item><title>Zettelkasten</title><link>https://braindump.badykov.com/notes/20210831214301-zettelkasten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://braindump.badykov.com/notes/20210831214301-zettelkasten/</guid><description>Zettelkasten is a note-taking and personal knowledge management method
Tools that implement this method:
Org-Roam - Emacs package. Uses org-mode files Roam research - Commercial note taking tool Obsidian - Commercial note taking tool but it uses markdown files. So users can keep their notes You can check ideas behind Zettelkasten in my blog post</description></item></channel></rss>